# **Atul Anand**

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Self-motivated and hardworking engineering graduate having more that one year experience in developing and managing software application using Java, Spring and ReactJS. Seeking to implement proven skills for the growth of the organization. Strong analytical and problem-solving skills.

atul.anand1811@gmail.com

+91-8809018608

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/atul-anand-1681151a1/

## **SKILLS**

Java Spring FrameWork ReactJS MySQL

Python MongoDB **Data Science** 

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Software Engineer

Cognizant Technology Solution Mar 2021 - Present

- Metlife- Japan
  - o Role Java FSE
  - Responsibility Developing Microservice architecture application.
  - o TechStack Java, Spring, JPA, ReactJS
- Metlife-US
  - o Role Java FSE
  - Responsibility Defect Fixing and Code Deployment
  - o TechStack ReactJS, Groovy, MongoDB

#### Frontend Developer - Intern

Acupace Technology May 2020 - Jul 2020

- Role- UI Developer
- Responsibility UI Development for Video Conferencing Application
- TechStack Ionic

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Technology**

IES College Of Technology, Bhopal Aug 2017 - May 2021

Stream - CSE

CGPA - 8.46

#### Intermediate

Doon Senior Secondary School May 2014 - May 2016 Percentage - 76%

#### Matriculation

Trident Public School Apr 2013 - Apr 2014 CGPA - 9.0

## **PROJECTS**

## **Smart Driving**

- Developed Machine Learning Model to detect drowsiness and reduce distractions while driving.
- TechStack Python, Twilio Platform, Camera Module, Rasberry Pi, Pytts and FacialLandMark Library.
- Won prize @13th ISEC, IIIT Jabalpur

#### **Lets Connect**

- Developed one to one video calling application.
- TechStack ReactJs, ExpressJS, SocketIO
- Working App:- https://frabjous-pie-cab044.netlify.app/

#### MyShopCart

- An online shopping web application, where user can search and order different category of products.
- TechStack: Spring, ReactJS, MySQL

#### Voice Assistance

- A CLI based application which responds according to the voice commands given by the user.
- TechStack Python

## CERTIFICATION

#### **Data Science using Python**

Internshala

Credential ID: 2D8CB593-F5A4-4F28-22FA-72BCD3A197ED

**Credential URL:** https://trainings.internshala.com/verify\_certificate

#### Python Skill Certificate by HackerRank

HackerRank

Credential ID: - atul\_anand1811

Credential URL: https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/ba5d2a9413a3

## HackerRank Skill Certificate

HackerRank

Credential ID: 07B447E4D373

Credential URL:- https://www.hackerrank.com/certificates/07b447e4d373

#### **Critical Thinking Strategies for Better Decisions**

**NASBA** 

Credential ID: UC-b0f2d7a0-9dc7-4d48-8307-09c1fb8abc4b

**Credential URL**: udemy-certificate.s3.amazonaws.com/pdf/UC-b0f2d7a0-9dc7-4d48-8307-09c1fb8abc4b.pdf

# **HOBBIES**

Chess Cricket